Finding Aid for First Presbyterian Church, Saline, Mich., Records, 1831-1985
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
First Presbyterian Church, Saline, Mich., records 1831-1985
First Presbyterian Church (Saline, Mich.)
2 linear ft.
86865 Ba 2
Session minute books, 1831-1982; record books of women's and youth organizations; collected historical records used in preparation for 125th and 150th anniversary celebrations; and photographs.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The church (donor no. 1690 ) first began depositing its records in 1942. Periodic additions have been made.
The record group is open to research.
The First Presbyterian Church of Saline was founded in 1831.
The record group consists of meeting and session records, 1831-1982; a church register, dating approximately from 1940 to 1987; records of church women's societies and other church organizations; historical and church anniversary materials; and financial records.
Subjects:
First Presbyterian Church (Saline, Mich.); Presbyterian Church (U.S.A.)--Michigan--Saline.; Saline (Mich.); Women--Michigan--Saline--Societies and clubs.; Youth--Michigan--Saline.; Youth--Religious life--Michigan--Saline.; Women--Religious life--Michigan--Saline.; Registers of births, etc.--Michigan--Saline.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Caldwell, William E.; Cemeteries--Michigan--Saline.; Churches--Michigan--Saline.; First Presbyterian Church (Saline, Mich.); Saline (Mich.)--Cemeteries.; Saline (Mich.)--Churches.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Meeting and session records
  - Record book, 1837-1856 (Box 1)
    (original and typescript)
  - Record book, 1837-1897 (Box 1)
    (copied from original)
  - Session record books, 1831-1982, 7 volumes (Box 1)
    - 1831-1846 (Box 1)
    - 1846-1870 (Box 1)
    - 1905-1933 (Box 1)
    - 1933-1955 (Box 1)
    - 1955-1963 (Box 1)
    - 1963-1975 (Box 1)
    - 1975-1982 (Box 1)
- Church register
  - 1940s-1980s (Box 1)
    (contains membership materials, marriages, baptisms, burials; the volume appears to be a recopying of earlier volumes; the information dates back to the early 1900s)
- Women's societies and other church organizations
  - Ladies Sewing Society, Treasurer's book, 1865-1901 (Box 2)
  - Women's organization record book, ca. 1913-1914 (Box 2)
  - Presbyterian Ladies Society, Record book, 1914-1950 (Box 2)
  - Ladies Aid Society minute book, 1927-1936 (Box 2)
  - Ladies Aid Society minute book, 1936-1950 (Box 2)
  - Ladies Aid Society minute book, 1950-1961 (Box 2)
  - Young People's Society of Christian Endeavor. Secretary's book, 1885-1899 (Box 2)
    (microfilm copy available)
  - Friendship class minute book, 1933-1937 (Box 2)
  - Sunday School record book, 1884-1890 (Box 2)
- Anniversaries and historical materials
  - Miscellaneous (includes published history, 1899 and 1931) (Box 2)
  - 125th Anniversary celebration materials, 1956 (Box 2)
  - Sesquicentennial anniversary, 1981 (Box 2)
  - Fellowship hall dedication, 1985 (Box 2)
  - Photographs (Box 2)
- Financial records
  - Ledger, 1880-1897 (Box 2)
  - Treasurer's accounts, 1898-1912 (Box 2)
  - Record of weekly offerings, 1891-1896 (Box 2)